A Guide to the Henry H. Douglas Collection, 1861-1978
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
- Series 2: Negatives
  - Sub-series 2-3: Falls Church Historical News and Notes, 1967-1973
    - Part of the Falls Church yard in 1929. The Jachonias Lewis Shotwell house is at the right. It was demolished in the mid-50s. The stones, from left, are those of Mary E. Mills (1822-1887); Henry Fairfax, Julien and Jennie Desrochers; and the oldest (Carolin) stone at right. (v. 2, no. 3, p. 48), Undated (Box 3)
    - Julia Laurette Smith Auchmoody probably around 1900. She died March 3, 1911, at 83. (v. 1, no. 6, p. 4) (2 of 2), Undated (Box 3)
    - Julia Laurette Smith Erwin as a young woman. She was born April 21, 1928. (v. 1, no. 6, p. 4) (1 of 2), Undated (Box 3)
    - The Walker house and outbuildings, 2124 Great Falls Street, Falls Church, about 1900. The large section was built in the late 1800s. The section back of the large section was the original house. The view is from Great Falls and Haycock Roads. (v. 2, no. 1, p. 1), Undated (Box 3)
    - At right: Goldie May (Elliott) Thompson. From left: Grace (Thompson) Sparrow (George C. Thompson's sister); Matilda (Elliott) True; and Ida Rebecca (Elliott) Erwin, Maynard Erwin's mother. October 5, 1950. (v. 2, no. 1, p. 2), Undated (Box 3)
    - William Henry Ellison was a native of Falls Church. He was a student at the old Jefferson School. He later studied for and entered the ministry on the west coast. Feeling that he was not effective in the church, he turned to education and became a very popular teacher. He was long associated with the University of California. ca 1920. (v. 2, no. 1, p. 5), Undated (Box 3)
    - Goldie May (Elliott) Thompson with her husband, George Cleveland Thompson. 1944. (v. 2, no. 1, p. 10), Undated (Box 3)
    - The Kiessling family in 1959. Left to right: Peter, Debbie, Dr. Oscar, Dr. Alice, Julie, Brenda, and Douglas. (v. 2, no. 3, p. 40), Undated (Box 3)
    - From left to right: Ellison/Rust store/Brock Lawn Mower Shop. West End Post Office/Shreve offices; Shreve warehouse and coal shed, Falls Church. early 1950s. (v. 2, no. 2, p. 16), Undated (Box 3)
    - The Falls Church Post Office in the 100 block of East Broad Street, about 1898. Luke Thompson is standing second from left. The others are unidentified. ca 1898. (v. 2, no. 2, p. 28), Undated (Box 3)
    - "Maury", the old Bailey mansion near Bailey's Cross Roads. People are unidentified. (v. 2, no. 3, p. 31), Undated (Box 3)
    - Poster for St. James' Players, Falls Church, printed in the Fairfax Herald in 1932. (v. 2, no. 3, p. 52), Undated (Box 3)
    - Federal Cavalry at The Falls Church during the Civil War. Photo by Matthew Brady, 1862. (v. 2, no. 4, p. 62), Undated (Box 3)
    - Harmon blacksmith shop on East Fairfax Street near The Falls Church. Mr. Harmon (right) and Henry Simms are in front. 1946. (v. 2, no. 4, p. 53), Undated (Box 3)